(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 10x03 - Frontier in Space (Episode 2)
《神秘博士》老版第十季第三集 太空边境 (第二部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
GARDINER: Earth battle cruiser to Earth cargo ship number C982,
地球巡航舰呼叫地球货船C982
we're now approaching you. Do you read me? Over.
我们正在靠近你船, 是否听到
Earth battle cruiser to Earth cargo ship number C982,
地球巡航舰呼叫地球货船C982
we are now approaching you. Do you read me?
我们正在靠近你船, 是否听到
Do you read me?
你们能听到吗?
Prepare to be boarded. Repeat. Prepare to be boarded.
准备接受登船. 重复, 准备接受登船
Do you read me? Over.
你们能听到吗? 完毕
Hello, battle cruiser, battle cruiser, this is the cargo ship. Over.
你好, 战斗巡航舰, 战斗巡航舰, 这里是货船. 完毕
What is your situation?
你们当前情况怎么样?
The ship has been attacked and the cargo stolen. Over.
货船被攻击了, 货也被劫走了. 完毕
Do you have casualties?
你们是否有伤亡?
Yes, the crew are stunned but otherwise they're unharmed. Over.
有, 船员被击晕了, 不过其他人未受伤害. 完毕
We shall lock on. Five seconds from now.
我们即将对接锁定, 还有5秒
DOCTOR: It's all right, Jo.We're being rescued.
没事了, Jo. 我们得救了
- What happened? - Now don't worry, old chap.
- 发生了什么? - 别担心, 老伙计
You'll be all right.
你很快就没事了
Draconians! They're boarding!
龙族人! 他们要上船了!
- Stewart? Who are you? - Passengers.
- Stewart? 你们是谁?  - 乘客
I see. Having a fancy-dress party? What happened?
我明白了, 在开化妆舞会? 刚才什么情况?
- Dragons attacked us. - Did they get the cargo?
- 那些龙袭击了我们 - 他们劫走货物了没
- I don't know. - Yes, they took everything.
- 我不清楚 - 是的, 他们全拿走了
Including some rather valuable property of mine.
包括我个人的一些相当值钱的东西
- Well, tough luck. - Oh, thank you very much.
- 嗯, 运气不好 - 哦, 很感谢你们
- Dragons... They attacked us. - Yes, we know.
- 那些龙...他们攻击了我们 - 是的, 我们知道了
You say you're passengers.
Isn't that a little unusual on a cargo ship?
你说你们是乘客, 这对于一艘货船来讲是不是有点不合常理啊?
Well, we're here, aren't we?
但是, 我们现在就在这里, 对不?
Where did you pick these two up?
你们在哪里捎带上他们俩的?
I don't know. I can't seem to remember...
我不知道, 好像想不起来了...
Pull yourself together! How did they get on board?
站好了! 他们是怎么上船的?
Stowaways... That's it, they were stowaways.
偷渡的... 对了, 他们是偷渡的
- They were sending messages. - That's right.
- 他们曾经往外发送信息 - 那就对了
They were helping the Dragons. They're traitors!
他们在帮助那些龙, 他们是叛徒!
But that's absolute nonsense.
这绝对是胡说
Look, we didn't want to be on this ship. It was an accident.
是这样, 我们并不想到这艘船上来的, 是一次事故
You said you were passengers.
你刚说你们是乘客
I was merely trying to avoid a lot of tiresome explanations, old chap.
我只是想把事情弄简单一点, 免得浪费半天口舌, 老伙计
Stewart, I'll leave Kemp on board to take your ship back to Earth.
Stewart, 我把 Kemp 留在船上, 带你们回地球
What about these two?
这两个人怎么办?
Lock them in the hold, put a guard on them.
把他们所进置留室, 派人看着他们
- But we haven't done anything.
- They say you have. Take them away.
- 但我们没干过任何事啊 - 他们说你干过. 带走
Now, if you'll only listen to me...
诶, 如果你能听我说...
You can talk to Earth Security.
你跟地球安全部去说吧
They'll listen, it's their business.
他们会听的, 这是他们的工作
- Put them in the starboard cubicle. - All right, get moving.
- 把他们带到右舷小隔间去 - 好的, 走
In there.
进去
Oops. No need to push.
噢, 没必要推啊
(SHIPS UNLOCKING)
Listen. The ships, they're unlocking.
听, 他们脱离了
Still watching the door.
还在门口看着呢
That's what he's there for, isn't it?
他在那儿就是干这个的, 对吧
Right, we'll give it a few minutes,
对了, 我们再等个几分钟
then I'll start groaning and pretending I'm ill,
我就开始嚎叫, 假装我病了
when he comes in you can use your Venusian karate.
等他一进来, 你就用你的金星搏击术
- And then what? - Then we'll take his gun,
- 然后呢?  - 然后我们就拿下他的枪
go to the flight deck and make somebody take us back to Earth.
冲到飞行甲板, 强迫莫个人带我们回地球去
Jo, this ship's already going back to Earth.
Jo, 这艘船已经在往地球飞了
Oh. Oh, dear. Hmm.
噢, 噢, 天啊, 唔
Hey, I've got a terrific idea.
嘿, 我有了一个绝妙的主意
I saw this film once, you see, and there were these two big gangsters,
我在一部电影里面看过, 里面有两个大块头的黑帮分子
big fellas they were, with sort of cauliflower ears...
他俩都是大块头, 都带有一对招风耳...
- Look, Jo! - And one of them...
- 嘿, Jo! - 其中一个人...
Will you stop pacing up and down like a perishing panda.
你能不能不要像个暴躁的熊猫一样来回踱步
Now, come and sit down. Let me think, will you?
现在, 过来坐下来, 让我来想一想, 行吗?
That's better.
这样好多了
Doctor, well, now the Ogrons have gone,
博士, 对了, 既然 Ograns 已经走了
why don't the crewmen remember what really happened?
为什么这些船员还是想不起来真正发生了什么?
Because the true facts have been erased from their minds, that's why.
因为真相已经从他们大脑里面抹掉了, 这就是为什么
Well, yes, but why did they keep telling lies about us?
哦, 这样, 但为什么他们又一直说胡说八道呢?
Oh, they don't know that they're lying, Jo.
哦, 他们并不知道他们在胡说八道, Jo
They're desperately trying to fit us into their version of things.
他们只是在尽力地把我们装进他们那个版本的真实中去
Well, what are we going to do then?
那, 我们该怎么办?
Well, when we get back to Earth,
现在, 等我们回到地球
we've got to reach someone in authority
whose mind isn't already closed.
我们应该能碰到某个当权者, 他的大脑没有那么封闭?
Closed to what?
封闭?
Jo, look, these people believe
Jo, 你看, 这些人相信
that the Draconians are attacking their spaceships, right?
是龙族人袭击了他们的飞船, 对吧?
- Right. - We know that they're wrong, don't we?
- 是的   - 我们知道他们说的是错的, 是不?
Well, yes, it was Ogrons.
嗯, 是的, 是 Ogrons 干的
Oh, we also know that the Ogrons couldn't possibly
我们也知道 Ogrons 不太可能
have created that hallucinatory device
能制造出那种致幻设备
that makes the Earthmen think they're Draconians.
可以让地球人产生错觉, 以为是龙族人袭击了他们
Oh. Oh, well, that's simple then.
哦, 哦, 这样就简单了
I mean, what we've got to is find out what's going on,
我是说, 我们要做的, 就是搞明白到底是怎么一回事
who's behind the Ogrons, where they've taken the TARDIS,
谁在操纵这些 Ogrons, 他们又把 TARDIS 带到哪里去了
go and get it back and then we can all go home.
我们去把它找回来, 然后我们就可以回家了
- Right? - Right.
- 对吧?  - 对
Oh. I don't know what I've been worrying about.
哦, 我不知道一直在担心什么
We are now in space port 10.
我们正在十号太空站
The ship will land in 15 minutes. The crew are safe.
飞船将在15分钟内降落, 船员都安全
Also aboard, two human stowaways, origins unknown.
船上还有两个偷渡的人类, 来源未知
I want a cordon around the landing area,
the minute that ship touches down.
我需要飞船一着地, 就在周边拉起警戒线
Nobody on, nobody off till I get there.
在我到达之前, 任何人不得进入, 任何人不得离开
Sir.
先生
I'd better get down there.
I want handle the preliminary interrogations myself.
我最好还是下去, 我想亲自进行初步的审讯
Good.
好
General Williams, whatever you find out you'll report directly to me.
Williams 将军, 无论你发现什么, 都要直接报告给我
Naturally.
当然
Now, if you'll excuse me.
现在, 我先退下了
What did they think they're doing?
他们以为他们在干什么?
We've been landed for simply ages.
我们都已经落地好几个世纪了
Well, 12 minutes, to be exact, Jo.
哦, 12 分钟, 严格地说, Jo
(SHUSHING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Someone's coming.
有人来了
- Outside. - We want to see somebody in authority.
- 出来 - 我们要见你们老大
You're going to, but outside.
你会见到的, 不过得先出来
Now then, what's all this about?
既然这样, 这些又什么意思
- Draconian agents? Are you sure? - What else can they be?
- 龙族特工? 你确定吗?   - 要不然还能是什么
Their story is obvious nonsense.
他们的故事显然说不通啊
But why? We...
为什么? 我们...
Why would the Draconians leave them on board the ship?
为什么龙族人会把他们继续留在飞船上?
The Draconians are preparing for war.
那些龙族人正在准备一场战争
You're still only suspecting that. There is no proof.
你这只是在怀疑, 但没有证据
Then they need to plant human agents,
所以他们需要安插两名人类特工
traitors, on this planet to sabotage our war effort.
两个叛徒, 好让他们在这个星球上破坏我们的反击
But we are bound to suspect them. They must have realised.
但我们肯定会怀疑他们啊, 他们肯定能想到这个
The Draconians probably thought the crew was dead.
那些龙族人也许认为船员都死了
We could easily have accepted those two as passengers,
以为我们会轻易地相信这两个家伙真的是乘客
two unfortunate refugees from a Draconian attack,
是两个躲避龙族人袭击的不幸难民
ideally placed for espionage.
完美地为间谍活动安插下来
If you are right,
the sooner we confront the Draconians with this, the better.
如果你是对的, 我们跟龙族人的硬碰硬, 就越早越好
(INTERCOM BEEPING)
Bring the prisoners in.
把俘虏带进来
We'll bring them face to face with the Draconian ambassador.
我们要带他们跟龙族大使来个面对面
In there.
进去
- When did you last eat? - Quite some while ago.
- 你上次什么时候吃饭的? - 有些时候了
Well, I'll see they send you some food.
好吧, 我去让他们给你们送点食物进来
I'd like to get a message through to your president.
我期望给你们的总统带个信息
Not a chance.
别妄想了
I'm going straight back to my ship.
我就直接回我的船了
Don't want to get mixed up with security.
别想着破坏这里的安保设施
It's not healthy.
这对你不好
- Look, I'll give you a piece of advice. - DOCTOR: Yes?
- 对了, 我要给你们一个小建议 - 什么...
Sooner or later, you're going to tell them everything.
或早或迟, 你们都给告诉他们全部实情
They'll use the mind probe. You talk to them now.
他们会使用思维探测器的, 你们还是现在就说实话吧
You'll save yourselves a lot of trouble.
这也可以给你们自己省去很多麻烦
A mind probe?
思维探测器?
Oh, you don't want to worry about those things, Jo.
哦, 你不用担心那个东西, Jo
As long as you tell 'em the truth, they can't do you any harm.
只要你告诉他们的的确是事实, 那东西伤害不到你的
- They can't? - No, of course not.
- 不能吗? - 不能, 当然不能
Well, they're only sort of computers with a few extra knobs on.
只是个电脑, 加了几个小球而已
And you know how stupid computers can be, don't you?
而且你也知道电脑有多笨的, 是吧?
Now come and sit down, stop worrying. Come on. Sit down.
现在过来坐下吧, 别担心.过来, 坐下
Did I ever tell you the story about
how I was once captured by the Medusoids?
我有没有告诉过你, 我曾经被 Medusoid 抓住过?
- What are they? - Medusoids?
- 被什么抓住?  - Medusoids
How can I describe them to you?
我怎么跟你说呢
Well, they're a hairy jellyfish with claws, teeth and a leg.
嗯, 他们就像水母, 很多头发, 但还是爪子, 牙齿, 还有一条腿
(EXCLAIMING IN DISGUST)
Anyway, they put me under one of these mind probes things, you see,
然后呢, 他们就把我弄到他们的思维探测器下面去了
and tried to get me to tell them where I was going.
一心想让我告诉他们我要去哪儿
So, I said I was on my way to meet a giant rabbit,
于是, 我说我只是要去见一只巨型兔子
a pink elephant and a purple horse with yellow spots.
一头粉色大象, 一匹带有黄色斑点的紫色马
(LAUGHING) What happened?
后来呢?
Well, the poor old machine just couldn't believe it,
哦, 那台可怜的机器完全不敢相信这个
- had a nervous breakdown. - And then what happened?
- 就崩溃了  - 再然后呢?
Well, they put me under another one of these mind probe things
哦, 他们又把我放到另外一台这样的思维探测器下
and the same thing happened.
一样的事情发生了
But you weren't telling the truth.
但你并没有说实话啊
I mean, you weren't really going to meet a giant rabbit,
我说, 你并不是真的要去见一只巨型兔子
a pink elephant and a... What was it?
一头粉色大象, 还有...什么来着
A purple horse with yellow spots. Yes, I was.
一匹带有黄色斑点的紫色马. 是的, 我是要去见
You see, they were all delegates
for the third Intergalactic Peace Conference.
你知道吗, 他们都是来参加第三次星际和平会议的代表
How did you get away from these things?
你怎么逃脱的呢?
Well, they had to turn me loose eventually.
噢, 最后他们不得不放了我
- Why?  - They ran out of mind probes.
- 为什么 - 他们的思维探测器用光了
(BOTH LAUGHING)
PRESIDENT: And you are quite sure it was a Draconian battle cruiser.
你确定那是一艘龙族战斗巡航舰吗?
Of course, Madam.
当然, 夫人
They locked on and boarded us.
他们锁定了我们, 强行登了船
We saw them. They were Draconians.
我们都看见了, 他们是龙族人
Thank you. That will be all.
谢谢你, 你们可以走了
I hope you will soon recover from your ordeal.
期望你很快从这些磨难中恢复过来
Well, Your Highness?
怎样, 殿下?
These men are your servants.
他们都是你的人
They are saying what they have been ordered to say.
你们让他们说什么, 他们就说什么
On this occasion, we have more than our servants to confront you with.
这次不同了, 能跟你对质的不仅仅是我们的人
We have captured two of your human agents.
我们抓住了你的两个人类间谍
We have no human agents.
我们没有人类间谍
Subversion and espionage are expressly forbidden
破坏与间谍活动是明令禁止的
by the treaty of peace between our two empires.
我们两国的和平条约已经写得很清楚了
A treaty which you have flagrantly broken.
这个条约已经被你们戳得千疮百孔了
I shall return to my embassy.
我回大使馆了
Just a moment please, Your Highness. Bring them in.
请等一下, 殿下. 把他们带进来
These people stowed away on the cargo ship.
这两个人偷渡在那艘货船上
They transmitted signals
他们往外面发信号
which enabled your battle cruiser to home in on its prey.
引导你们的战斗巡航舰过来实施攻击
I know nothing of this.
我对此毫不知情
Perhaps you do not,
but some servant of the Draconian empire employed them.
也许你是不知道, 但龙族帝国的某些人雇佣了他们
Madam, I can assure that I've never been employed by anybody.
夫人, 我可以保证, 我从来没有被任何人雇佣
Least of all by the Draconians.
更别说被龙族人雇佣了
Your servants should have been better rehearsed in their lies.
你的喽罗应该好好排练一下如何撒谎
Or they're showing a misguided loyalty to their Draconian masters.
或许他们只是对龙族主人展现了错误的忠诚 (fixme)
If we really were working for the Draconians,
如果我们真的是在为龙族人办事
why did they leave us in your ship?
他们怎么会把我们留在你们的船上
To act as spies when you were brought back to Earth.
为了方便你们被带回地球之后可以继续充当间谍
Allow me to congratulate you, sir.
请允许我祝贺你, 先生
You have the most totally closed mind that I've ever encountered.
你拥有我所见过的最封闭的头脑
Madam, I beg of you to listen to me.
夫人, 我请求你能听我说
Some third party is trying to provoke war
between Earth and Draconia.
某个第三方团体正试图挑起地球与龙族的战争
You are both being duped.
你们两边都被欺骗了
Take them away.
把他们带走
Just a minute, please.
请等一下
Why should a third party wish to do this?
为什么某个第三方团体想干这个
I've no idea, Madam,
我不知道, 夫人
but believe me, that is what is happening.
但相信我, 这就是真相
Take them away.
把他们带走
Now please listen to me! If you don't
现在请听我说! 如果你不听的话
you'll be involved in a war that could cause the death of millions.
你们就会卷入一场战争, 百万生灵将因此丧命
Is this the evidence upon which you accuse me?
这就是你们控诉我的证据?
I must ask you to convey a formal protest to your Emperor.
我必须要求你向你的皇帝转达我们的正式抗议
I shall inform him of this latest insult
to the honour of the Draconian empire.
我会告诉他的, 告诉他你们对龙族尊严的侮辱
We should have used the mind probe before we saw the ambassador.
我们在见大使之前应该使用思维探测器的
If we'd had a full confession...
如果我们拿到完整的坦白书...
Has it occurred to you that
they might have been speaking the truth?
你有没有想过, 或许他们说的是实情呢?
(SCOFFING) Is it likely?
这可能吗?
Mysterious alien giants that can change their form?
神秘的外星巨人可以改变他们的外形?
A pocket spaceship that appears inside another?
一艘可以出现在另外一艘飞船中的小型飞船?
I suppose you're right. It is nonsensical.
我觉得你是对的, 这太荒谬了
Just you leave them to me.
你就把他们交给我吧
I'll get the truth out of them, eventually.
我会从他们嘴里得到真相的, 不管怎样
Well, we've seen the President.
怎样, 我们已经见过了总统
I've got to get them to listen to me,
for their sakes as well as ours.
我必须得让他们能听进去我的话, 这为了他们好, 也为了我们自己
Well, why their sakes?
为什么为了他们好?
Well, that was a Draconian with the President, you know?
总统旁边有一个龙族人, 你没看见吗?
- Obviously an ambassador of some kind. - So?
- 显然是一个大使什么的 - 所以?
Well, clearly Earth and Draconia are on the brink of war,
显然地球和龙族之间的战争一触即发了
and they both believe it's the other's fault.
他们都相信是对方的错
Well, never mind about that. What about getting us out of here?
唉, 还是先别管那个了. 想想我们怎么出去
Well, I can but try.
我能, 不过得试试
Yeah, seems a fairly conventional type of electronic lock,
嘢, 看起来是相当传统的电子锁
rather old-fashioned really. Here goes.
真的相当老的款式, 来试试
(HIGH-PITCHED BEEPING)
(ALARM BLARING)
Yes, well, I think we'll sit here for a while after all.
好吧, 我想我们还是在这里坐一会儿
But why?
不过为什么?
Why should they produce such an elaborate lie?
为什么要编造一个如此复杂的谎言
The ways of the Earthmen are devious.
They're an inscrutable species.
地球人的行为很怪异, 他们这个种族真是难以揣测
Obviously, they are preparing the next stage of their plan.
很显然, 他们在为他们自己计划的下一步铺路
First, the attacks on our ships and now this.
首先, 攻击我们的船, 然后又是这个
Is it possible, Your Highness,
that for once the Earthmen spoke the truth?
有没有可能, 殿下, 这一次地球人说的是事实?
Some plan of the Emperor of which
Your Highness has not been informed?
皇帝有他自己的计划, 而没有告知殿下?
The Emperor would not possibly contemplate such a plan.
我们的皇帝不会弄出这样的计划
We do not break the treaty of peace.
我们不能打破和平协定
Shall I prepare your Excellency's report
to the Emperor on this meeting?
我可以去准备报告了吗, 您觐见皇帝陛下时的报告
I must have more information.
我必须获得更多的信息
It would be useful to question the humans who were found on the ship.
如果能审讯一下船上找到的那两个人, 应该会有帮助
They are supposed to be prisoners.
他们肯定被囚禁起来了
Prisoners have been known to escape, Your Highness.
被囚禁的人都是可以逃走的, 殿下
Not without help.
那得有人帮忙才行
And that would be a grave act of hostility.
而这可是严重的敌对行为
I could not possibly countenance such a plan.
我不可能支持这样的计划
But, should two escaping prisoners seek sanctuary in this embassy,
但是, 如果两个逃犯到大使馆来寻求庇护
it would be uncivilised to turn them away.
我们弃而不管就太不人道了
I must not detain you longer.
我就不再耽搁你了
No doubt you have duties demanding your attention?
无疑你现在还有更需要你关注的事情?
Your Highness.
殿下
(INTERCOM BEEPING)
Yes?
什么事?
The First Secretary from the Draconian embassy
龙族大使馆首席秘书
wishes to speak you, Madam President.
期望同您谈谈, 总统夫人
Very well.
好
I'm honoured that you consent to speak to me, Madam President.
很荣幸您同意同我谈话, 总统夫人
What is it that you wish to say?
你想同我说的是什么?
It concerns the two Earthmen
这关系到那两个地球人
who were found on board your cargo ship.
在你们货船上发现的那两个
Well?
怎样?
His Highness would like to question them
殿下想要找他们文化
in your presence, of course, Madam President.
当然, 是您也在场的前提下, 总统夫人
For what purpose?
目的是什么?
His Highness feels that such an interrogation
would help to convince you
殿下觉得这样的审讯有助于向你证明
that they are not agents of Draconia.
他们并不是龙族的间谍
I shall have them brought here immediately.
我让人立刻把他们带到这里来
I suggest His Highness joins me here.
We shall question them together.
我建议殿下也加入进来, 我们应该一起来询问
- On your feet. - Hmm, why?
- 站起来 - 为什么?
You heard me. Move.
你听到啦, 走
Not unless you give me some good reason.
不走, 除非你给我一个很好的理由
The President wants you. Is that good enough?
总统要见你们. 这个理由怎么样?
Perhaps she believed you?
也许她会相信你?
Are you sure it's the President
and not another ridiculous interrogation?
你确定是总统, 而不是其他什么荒唐的审讯官?
I said move!
我说了走!
Come on, Jo, perhaps we can convince them after all.
来吧, Jo, 也许我们最终能说服他们
DOCTOR: Move, Jo! Get up! Run!
走, Jo, 起来, 跑!
Quickly, the Doctor!
快, 博士!
But you don't understand!
但你不明白
It's the Draconians. They've got the Doctor.
是龙族人, 他们抓走了博士
We must demand the immediate withdrawal of the Draconian embassy.
我们必须要求立刻驱逐龙族大使馆
Break off diplomatic relations completely?
完全断绝外交关系?
What diplomatic relations?
什么外交关系?
The embassy staff have behaved like criminals.
这些使馆人员完全就是些匪徒
We don't know that the ambassador was behind this.
我们并不知道大使是否是始作俑者
The attackers were Draconians. They were clearly seen.
袭击者是龙族人, 大家都看得一清二楚
The Draconian embassy tricked you into moving the prisoners,
龙族使馆人员欺骗了你, 让你把那两个囚犯带出来
then mounted an armed attack in order to rescue their agents.
然后就安排了武装袭击, 救走了他们的间谍
- Is the girl here? - She's outside now.
- 那个女孩儿还在这里吗? - 她现在在外面
(INTERCOM BEEPING)
Bring the girl in. I wish to question her.
带那个女孩儿进来, 我想找她问话
And the closing of the Draconian embassy?
那关闭龙族大使馆的事情呢?
I do not intend to break off diplomatic relations.
我并没打算断绝外交关系
But surely there's no alternative once this news gets out.
很显然, 等新闻一出来, 我们就没有什么选择了
Then it mustn't, General Williams.
那它就不能出来, Williams 将军
It is your responsibility to ensure
你有这个责任确保
a complete security blackout on this incident.
这次事件不泄露丝毫出去, 为安全期间
Very well, Madam. Under protest.
好吧, 夫人. 但我表示抗议
You can go.
你可以走了
Come forward, my dear.
到前面来, 亲爱的
You realise that the escape of your colleague
你的同僚逃走了, 你应该能意识到
has left you in a very serious position?
这会让你陷入一个困难的境地吧
But he didn't escape, he was kidnapped!
他不是逃走, 他是被绑架了
He was rescued by your Draconian paymasters.
他是被你们龙族的雇主给救走了
The wisest course you can take now is to make a full confession.
你现在最明智的选择, 就是完全的坦白
Remember your colleague has left you to your fate.
记住, 你的同僚已经把你扔给了命运
But you've got it all wrong!
但你们完全都搞错了
You see, the Doctor was pleased when you sent for him
你看, 听说你找人带他过来, 博士是很高兴的
because he wanted to talk to you. And...
因为他想要告诉你情况, 而且...
We have eye-witness reports on what occurred.
到底发生了什么, 我们有目击者的报告
We need to know how you came to work for the Draconians.
我们想要知道你们是怎么开始为龙族人工作的
When were you recruited?
你们是在什么时候被招募的?
How many agents do they have on Earth?
他们在地球上有多少特工?
What are their plans?
他们的计划是什么?
If you tell us everything,
如果你把这些都告诉我们
I'll promise I'll see to it personally
that you will be treated leniently.
我保证我会确保你会得到宽大处理
But I don't know what you're talking about.
但我不知道你在说些什么
Look, we told you the truth when we first came here.
看, 我们一到这里就把事实告诉你们了
We're not working for the Draconians.
我们没有为龙族人工作
We're wasting time.
我们这是在浪费时间
I suggest you let me
apply depth interrogation techniques without delay.
我建议您立刻允许我使用其他审讯手段
Look, you can use your mind probe or whatever.
看, 你可以使用思维探测器什么的
I'm telling you the truth.
我说的都是事实
Well, I must say
it's very nice of you gentlemen to invite me here.
嗯, 我得说你们邀请我过来, 这一点很好
And where is Miss Grant?
不过Grant 小姐在哪儿?
Your companion is still with your fellow Earthmen.
你的同伴还跟你们地球人在一起
Don't you realise what you've done?
你明白你们做了什么吗?
You've now finally convinced them
that we're both Draconian agents.
你们最终向他们证实了, 我们俩都是龙族特工
There is no need to maintain this pretence.
没有必要再假装了
We know that you are both agents of the Earth government.
我们都知道你们俩都是地球政府的特工
You're part of a plot against the Draconian empire.
你们是整个图谋的一部分, 针对龙族帝国的图谋
My dear chap, I've already been through all this
with the President of Earth.
亲爱的伙计, 我已经经历过一遍这些了, 就在地球总统那边
She thinks I'm working for you.
而她认为我在替你们工作
- You are working for General Williams. - I'm what?
- 你在为 Williams 将军卖命 - 我在什么?
General Williams hates our people.
Williams 将军憎恨我们
Once before, he caused war between us and the Earthmen.
曾经有一次, 他挑起了我们和地球人的战争
Now he plans to do so again.
现在他打算再来一次
And such a war would be madness
since both empires will be destroyed.
这样的战争很愚蠢啊, 因为两边都会被毁灭
Yes, I couldn't agree with you more.
是的, 我相当赞同你的意见
That's exactly what I've been trying to say to you.
这也正是我一直想要跟你们说的
The Earth cargo ship was not attacked by Draconians.
地球货船并不是被龙族人攻击的
It was not attacked at all. The whole story is a lie!
它根本就没有被攻击, 这整个故事都是谎言!
I can assure you that it was attacked, but by Ogrons.
我想你保证它的确被攻击了, 不过是被 Ogrons
- Ogrons? - Yes.
- Ogrons? - 对
Some third party's employing them
某个第三方团队雇佣了他们
trying to make trouble between Earth and Draconia.
试图在地球和龙族之间制造争端
If you tell us the details of General Williams' plan,
如果你告诉我们 Williams 将军的详细计划
we shall be able to expose him to your President.
我们将会在你们的总统面前揭发他
There will still be a chance for peace.
这样还是有一丝和平的机会
My dear chap, nobody is more devoted to the cause of peace
than I am.
我亲爱的伙计, 没有人比我更热心于和平了
But I cannot tell you something that I don't know.
但我没办法告诉你我所不知道的事情
We have mind-probing techniques
我们有思维探测技术
just as efficient as those employed by you Earthmen.
跟地球人的一样高效
If you do not speak now, we shall force you to confess.
如果你现在不说, 我们会逼着你说
Don't you realise you're completely on the wrong tack?
你们怎么就不明白, 你们完全搞错重点了呢?
There is a plot, yes.
这里有阴谋, 是的
But the Earthmen are not behind it, any more than you are.
但后面不是地球人, 正如也不是你们
Take him away!
把他带走
No!
不
Stop him!
阻止他!
Halt!
停下
(DRACONIANS GROANING)
Hello, Jo.
你好, Jo
Doctor, where've you been?
博士, 你去哪儿了?
I've been paying a brief but unwilling visit
to the Draconian embassy.
去龙族大使馆进行了一个简短的参观, 不过不太情愿
And I'm afraid I had to leave in rather a hurry
于是我就着急地离开了
and found myself back here.
然后就发现我回到这里了
What happened?
发生了什么?
Well, believe it or believe it not, Jo,
哦, 不知道你相不相信, Jo
they think we're working for General Williams
and trying to provoke a war.
他们认为我们在为 Williams 将军工作, 在试图挑起一场战争
Oh, no!
噢, 不!
Yes, Earth is blaming Draconia and Draconia is blaming Earth.
是的, 地球人指责龙族人, 龙族人指责地球人
- And both sides are blaming us. - That's about it.
- 然后两边都指责我们 - 正是这样
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING)
What's the matter?
什么事?
Well, that sound, the one I heard on the cargo ship.
那个声音, 我在货船上听到过的那个
I think I can hear it again.
我想我又听到了
(HIGH-PITCHED BLEEPING CONTINUES)
JO: Ogrons!
Ogrons!
You, come!
你, 过来